Be extra careful if you're type B.
If you leave untreated, it can get worse and even be life threatening.
Turn it off! I don't like this kind of TV.
It's not that scary.
You should go and bathe.
Will I die too?
What?
You're only 6 years old. What're you talking about?
Sorry.
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことは　分かんない
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau nanika ga chigau
これって　犠牲とは違う　何かが違う
This is different from sacrificing, very different.
batsugeemu jaa nante omou wa nai
罰ゲームじゃあ　なんて思うわない
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
tte nande nanoka ha wakannai
って　なんでなのかは　分かんない
I can't really say well what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと　釈然としないけど
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nantemonjanai
キミの存在　今大事だ　なんてもんじゃない
but "important" cannot be used to describe your existence any more.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai
終わらないことなんて　この世のどこにもない
There's nothing that will last forever without coming to an end.
naku no ha tsurai janai no
泣くのは辛いじゃないの
Crying is a very painful thing
I know! Sweet drops! Sweet drops!
zutto yume mite itaine
ずっと　夢見ていたいね
I have always wanted to dream
motto yasashiku shitaine
もっと　優しくしたいね
To be able to be more gentle
kimi to iraretara happy!
キミと居られたら　happy!
Just being together with you is happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って　強いね
Girls are strong,
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど　時々　弱いね
but at times, they are weak.
bokura no negai ha happy! happy! happy...
僕らの願いは　happy! happy! happy...
Our wish is to be happy! Happy! Happy!
sonna hibi mo happy!
そんな日々も happy!
Such happy days!
Just wanna make you happy...
See you later.
This isn't going to work if I can't find a proper daycare soon.
I hear some big companies have facilities to look after children.
Yeah, what country is that?
Oh, Kawachi-san!
Hey.
Did you manage to get a girlfriend?
What?
Recently, you've been leaving especially early.
It's not because of that.
Didn't you always take the last train home?
You even got this year's sales record!
If this carries on...
Those figures aren't something that can be accomplished through momentum and willpower.
I'm only lucky, that's all.
My name is Daikichi after all.
Note: (大吉) Daikichi means "excellent luck."
Kawachi-san...
Wait for me!
Let me help you.
Sure, thank you.
The fourth floor, right?
Yep. You still doing well?
It's completely hopeless this year.
Even this guy is giving me stress.
I might start going bald.
It's tough once you leave down good results.
Say, Gotou-san, do you really have children?
Could you not judge by the height?
You're so small; I don't know how a kid could fit in there.
Even I don't remember.
He's already two years old.
Thank you, over there please.
Ah, I'll go with you.
No need for that.
Okay.
See you.
Still powerful as always.
It'd be great if Gotou-san were still in Sales.
She's older then me by a few years.
After her pregnancy, she stepped down so she could get home earlier.
There were lots of rumours in the company about it.
What?!
How long will you be taking care of her?
I don't really know.
Rin-chan?
She's been frequently wetting her bed recently.
I noticed she seems pretty embarrassed about it.
It could be psychological.
But you know, small kids sweat quite a surprising amount.
Though they'll sweat less in fall and winter.
So they'll have to go to the bathroom more often.
Oh, my mom used to tell me to visit the toilet before I went to bed.
Her mother must really be worried...
I didn't get a chance to ask her.
Looks like mothers are really important.
A grown man shouldn't be saying such depressing stuff.
Go for it!
What did you play today?
Looked at picture books, and made silly faces.
I see. Was it fun?
What are you doing?
Rin~
I'll prepare dinner right away.
The moon is shrinking.
Hello?
So how's it going? Doing well?
Yup, I'm fine.
I'm not asking about you.
Oh, she's good.
Anyway, what's up with you?
I thought you didn't want to get yourself into trouble?
I can't just do nothing, since she's staying at your place.
I'm coming over this weekend to search for clues about Rin's mother.
I see.
Give me a call once you reach the bus stop.
Make sure she wears extra layers.
Okay. I'll call Haruko to come.
Rin seems to get along well with her kid.
Oh, it went past another car!
You look happy.
Yeah.
I'm back!
Welcome home.
So you're here, Rin-chan.
Hey.
I'm really sorry.
There's nothing here that little children will enjoy.
She prefers the sort of stuff that adults eat.
Right?
Are you done already?
Yes.
I don't care if you get hungry later.
I can't eat any more.
Sorry for having leftovers.
I'm back! Sorry I'm late!
They are the worst!
What's with that annoying woman and her kid?
Onii-chan! You really took her home?
Yeah.
The weather report next.
Today, the entire country will experience warm weather.
The surrounding temperatures have increased by 2 degrees...
I'm only going to the toilet.
...compared to previous years.
Next up will be the weather for tomorrow.
I said I'm going to the toilet.
I can't go with you there.
Is she normally like this?
Nope, she's pretty talkative at home.
She also seemed to be having fun on the train, as though she's going on a holiday.
But the moment she came, she saw the strict aunties and uncles who were at the funeral.
What did we do wrong!?
Idiot.
When adults are in a bad mood, the kids will feel it's their fault.
Children are indeed like that.
Both of you probably used to be like that.
Look! Even a thick-headed person like you felt this way.
Rin is definitely more intelligent than you.
Shut up, baldhead!
Rin-chan, you like Cat's Cradle, right?
Hey, at least give a reply.
Yeah.
This is for Rin-chan.
It's pretty.
Aunty will show you how to do it.
"Aunty", you say?
Shouldn't it be "Granny" instead?
You don't look like a granny at all.
Wow, what a good girl.
I guess this kid's idea of "old" is much older than normal.
Okay now, watch carefully.
Oh dear, did I do it wrongly?
Oh my.
This? The 4-step-ladder.
The 2-step-ladder.
Air plane.
Slide.
Diamond.
Impressive.
The strings are easy to move.
Did you make these yourself?
That's right. I knitted them using some fine wool thread.
Compared to using pure wool threads, the weight is just right.
That's right.
Since you have such articulate hands, you should be able to handle beanbags.
Use your little finger and hook it here.
Like this?
Yes.
One bean bag~ two bean bags-
What's going on here?
Never mind, we should be asking you why you're dressed like that.
Coming!
Who?
It's probably Haruko-san with her child.
Rin-chan!
It's beautiful, what are these?
They are called bean bags.
Thank you for today.
It's nothing.
But working and raising her at the same time, you're incredible.
The one at my place doesn't help at all.
Are you going to Grandpa's place later?
Yeah, I want to see if there are any leads about Rin's mother.
That's right.
It's easy to manipulate.
I think mothers are really important.
You do this and then that.
That's strange.
Grandpa, you should have written a Will before you died.
Weren't you worried about Rin?
Modem?
I'm back!
W-What's with that hairstyle of yours?!
I tied it to be the same as Reina-chan.
And what's with the clothes?
They're Kazumi Onee-chan's.
What? Kazumi?
Mom!
Such old-fashioned stuff won't suit modern kids.
Look! It really does suit her.
Well, it's not too bad.
Modern kids with this body style, in old clothes, feels pretty fashionable.
How nostalgic.
Did you find any clues at Grandpa's place?
None at all. I couldn't find anything.
I see.
No matter what, I think it's best you don't rush yourself to ask her about this.
Okay.
You're doing your best.
What?
Maybe I haven't told you before.
Your mother was actually still working after you were born.
She wasn't a full time housewife all along?
When she was pregnant with Kazumi, she was hospitalised for a while after overworking herself.
She realised her position was gone after returning to her company.
Your mother was really upset.
Kazumi was still very small after birth.
She always had to take days off or leave early to look after you two.
What about Kazumi?
Because she gave up everything for Kazumi, she grew up so unreasonable and spoiled.
Are you all right?
Do you want your dad to send you off?
It's fine. We'll make it there by foot.
Can I still come again?
She asks if she can visit again?
Aunty will be waiting for you.
You can come any time.
Well then.
W-What are you saying!?
Isn't it nice to have a grandchild?
You can leave the child to me.
It's impossible to raise a kid and work at the same time.
The women will surely be on the losing end.
I still want to wear a swimsuit, or go out drinking.
Hey Rin, did Grandpa own a computer?
You know what a computer is, right?
Yeah.
Then, did Grandpa use one before?
The assistant is the one who used the computer.
There was an assistant?
The assistant, Masako-san.
W-What kind of person was she?
I don't really remember.
I don't like Masako-san.
Because she hates me and always gets angry at me.
She's very scary, so I forgot about her.
I see.
It might be too late to say this now, but working while raising a child at the same time is really tough.
That's right. You were clueless.
Have you ever felt like you're sacrificing yourself for your child?
Are you referring to my job transfer?
Sorry, I guess it was rude to ask.
I felt this was the best choice at the time.
It turned out fine, so it's all right I guess.
Even if I really felt that way, I'd never say it.
Because the power of words is very strong.
I believe it's called the Power of Language.
Is it a bit too abstract?
No. Amazingly, I understand it somehow.
I'm counting on you to teach me more kid related stuff.
Your kid is even older, Kawachi-kun.
I actually want some advice from you, Senpai.
Rin, it's all right for you to wake me up.
But it's just sweat!
I don't care if it's sweat or anything; it doesn't matter.
Did you have a nightmare?
What is it like to die?
Daikichi, will you die before me?
The misery of Grandpa's death.
Her anxiety of what happens if I were to die too.
Coupled with her fear of death.
It's become a mess because she's unable to sort them out.
I'll be fine until you grow up to be a big sister.
When will I become a big sister?
No, I'll still be fine even until you become an aunty.
Before all that happens, I will never die.
So don't worry.
Wetting the bed is no big deal.
It'll be fine if you visit the toilet before sleep.
I'm afraid of the toilet.
I'll accompany you at night.
If you still wet the bed, you just have to change your clothes.
Will you be angry?
There's nothing to be angry about, or laugh about.
What did you want to talk to me about?
Pardon me for being so sudden, Hidaka-san.
It might sound a bit sudden.
Please transfer me to a section without overtime.
What? Kawachi! Are you serious?
I'm dead serious.
I see, something like that happened.
I personally feel it's a pity.
But, I have children of my own, too.
I'll try my best to speak to the chief about your request.
I'm sorry.
I'm counting on you.
But those people below will start making a fuss.
I won't accept this!
Why must it be Kawachi-san?!
Can't you just ask your relatives for help?
There's no way I can tell him that I decided to raise her at the spur of the moment.
Doesn't the daycare stay open late?
I don't want to be under anyone besides you.
I admit that it may be too sudden.
Superiors transferring suddenly is something pretty common.
Don't be so stubborn about it.
But I'm still really sorry.
Even without me around, my section will eventually return to normal.
Either that or the whole company fails.
But Rin doesn't work like that, that's what I feel.
My thinking should be correct, probably...
Are you done?
Yeah, is this much rich enough?
Yes, just nice.
Towel, lunch box, indoor slippers, toothbrush, cup and names are already written.
Admission guidebook
Futon!? Only the infants need them.
All right!
Daikichi, hurry up!
Right now, I'd be lying if I said this wasn't a sacrifice.
But as long as I don't regret this while looking back a few years down the road, it'll be fine.
nichiyou no hare ta hiru sagari
日曜の晴れた昼さがり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通い慣れたいつもの道が眩しく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らす暖かい太陽と　隣に君がいれば
The warm sun shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Feeling merry
utae Life Life Life
歌え　Life　Life　Life
Sing life, life, life
koe ha dokomade mo
声はどこまでも
I can hear our voices anywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Riding on the soaring wind
utae Life Life Life
歌え　Life　Life　Life
Sing life, life, life
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
Rin!
That picture you have on the hand towel and lunch box...
What's that?
It looks like some sort of big-eared dog.
It's not a dog!
It's a Lop Ear.
Lop- what's that?
Rabbit!
What? Isn't this a spotted dog?
A rabbit!
Seriously!
Rin, go take a piss.
I already went.
Oh, I see.